Bruce Lee, yes, he was a world-class
martial artist, but he was a very
deep person in how he thought about life
and meaning of life. Reading his
philosophies has always had a major
impact. The Tao of Jeet Kune Do is his
first martial arts book, but there's a
lot of stuff on Bruce Lee about how he
lived life and all that. And one quote
that comes to mind is he said many years
ago when he was alive, "Don't pray for
an easy life. Pray for the strength to
endure a hard one." And the meaning of
that, why would you want to do that? You
pray for the strength for a hard one
because a hard life is often a
meaningful life. Love, pain, suffering
because you're pursuing something
oftentimes bigger than yourself that
involves love, pain, and suffering such
that the path is going to be hard.
Praying for an easy life means you
wasted your potential as a human being.
I have an easy life meaning I never was
given a challenge, I was in the lap of
luxury my whole life, or whatever it is.
I had food on my plate, I never went
through any adversity.